RYAN C ANDERSON - WEB DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Ryan C. Anderson is web developer passionate about problem solving and writing elegant and efficient code. While he presently mostly writes in Ruby and Javascript, he has interest and past experience in a wide variety of frameworks and languages. In addition, he has a love and talent for learning new technologies and working in a team.

PROJECTS

Aggredile – Personal Project – <u>www.aggredile.com</u> - (2014 – Present)

- · Minimalistic Feedly clone, written using Rails and Backbone.js.
- · News aggregator, allowing users to subscribe to and follow RSS feeds.
- Designed and implemented database to hold user authentication and feed information.
- Designed and implemented RESTful api to control interaction between client and host.

Asteroids and Lasers - Personal Project - www.rycander.com/asteroids - (2014 - Present)

- Game written in Javascript, inspired by Asteroids.
- Wrote game from the ground up using Javascript and html5 canvas.

Sonar – University of California – www.sonar-game.com - (2011 - 2012)

- Survival/stealth game with a blind protagonist, written in C# using XNA.
- · Created level loading system, and collision handling/detecting system.
- · Designed and implemented data mining system exporting game info to xml.
- Designed and implemented a heat map program using data from xml.

WORK EXPERIENCE

INTEL – Junior Engineer (2013 - 2014)

- Worked as part of a scrum team meant to maintain a Ruby test suite that generated assembly to be run on prototype graphics hardware.
- Was responsible for identifying and repairing tests that were failing due to errors in test logic.

KATO – Software Engineer (2014 - 2015)

- Worked to help clean up new user experience for chat web client.
- Worked to help transition client from being written in Javascript and Knockout.js to being written in Typescript and React.

EDUCATION

B.S. in Computer Science – University of California Santa Cruz (2008 - 2012) App Academy graduate (2014)

SKILLS

Agile Scrum, Backbone.js, Bootstrap, C, C++, C#, CSS, Eclipse, Git, HTML, Jasmine, Java, Javascript, JSON, jQuery, Linux, OpenGL, Mac OS, PERL, PostreSQL, Python, Rails, Rspec, Ruby, SQLite, SVN, TDD, UML Design, Visual Studio, Windows, XML, XNA

CONTACT

Phone: (510) 325-5311
Email: ryan@rycander.com
Portfolio: rycander.com

GitHub: github.com/rycander

LinkedIn: <u>linkedin.com/pub/ryan-anderson/37/36a/61a</u> Location: 1963 Clemens Rd, Oakland, CA 94602